Kathleen Bull

BNatSc(AnimSc)
Veterinary Nurse
Currently: Masters of Wildlife Health and Conservation
4 Windarra Place, Castle Hill, NSW, AUSTRALIA, 2154
+61 431 711 840
kbull246@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

My name is Kathleen (Kitty) Bull and I am 26 years old. I am a Veterinary Nurse from Australia and I have a deep respect and passion for Veterinary Medicine and wildlife health.

I love traveling, eating food, exercise and meeting likeminded peoples. I have a wide variety of animals at home, including 8 cats, 3 dogs, chickens, ducks, snakes and birds. I enjoy bush walks, swimming and spending time with my animals outdoors. I have had an affinity with animals since I was a child and I spent most of my life riding horses and spending time on my family's farm. I am enthusiastic and awkward; I always try my best, give everything 100% of my effort, and I thrive when I am put under pressure.

I graduated among the top of my class in my Bachelor of Natural Science (Animal Science/Zoology) degree and continue to work hard to grow as an individual and a professional in the industry of veterinary medicine. My overarching goal is to gain entry into a degree of Veterinary Medicine by the end of 2020, and to one-day work in South Africa as a Veterinarian.

My love and knowledge of cheetah's has grown over the last two years, as I carried out an extensive research project on their stress physiology and reproduction throughout 2019 as part of my Bachelor degree. This research was conducted on behalf of a cheetah conservation organisation named the Wild Cat Conservation Centre in NSW, Australia.

I have previously travelled to South Africa with University on two occasions, and completed a solo trip in South Africa too. I view the country as my home away from home, even after being stung on the mouth by a spider eating wasp on a game drive in the Kruger National Park, came face to face with a black mamba in Skukuza, and swimming close up with great white sharks in Cape Town. Carrying out and assisting with surgery, being out in the field, anaesthesiology, stress physiology, pathology and conservation work are just a few examples of what I love doing.

It has been a dream of mine to complete Veterinary work within South Africa, and I would love to utilise my skills and knowledge to assist in the work that you do. I want nothing more than to be able to learn first-hand from being able to undertake a placement within your organisation.

Kathleen Bull

Resume and CV

CAREER PROFILE

I have worked in the veterinary industry for one and a half years, and am currently working as a Veterinary Nurse at a Greencross Veterinary Clinic and Rouse Hill Family Vets in NSW, Australia. I have volunteered previously in animal emergency, at Taronga Zoo, and in equine veterinary care. I currently volunteer for WIRES (Wildlife Rescue and Rehabilitation), and am a certified rescuer and carer. I have assisted in the treatment and care of a large range of clientele, and work for a veterinary practitioner that specialises in palliative care, in home euthanasia and acupuncture.

I have completed a Bachelor's degree in Natural Science (Animal Science) (graduation ceremony held April 2020) with a GPA of 5.957.

I have conducted research on cheetah stress physiology on behalf of the Wild Cat Conservation Centre in NSW, to aid in the continuation of their captive cheetah breeding programs. I have volunteered as a teacher's assistant and demonstrator while studying at Western Sydney University in laboratory settings and in the field for previously completed units from my bachelor's degree.

I have also volunteered on the Western Sydney University farms working with livestock and deer.

I am currently studying a Master of Wildlife Health and Conservation at Murdoch University, and aspire to make my way into Veterinary Medicine by 2021. Atop of this, I have completed my veterinary industry Fear Free Certification and my tranquilliser (chemical capture) and blow dart certification and my firearms license.

I am trustworthy, highly responsive and consistent. I am empathetic, and I am a calm, focussed, and hardworking individual. I thoroughly enjoy learning, challenging myself and achieving the best results that I can in all that I do.

EDUCATION

2020 - Current	Master of Wildlife Health and Conservation Murdoch University
2018 - Current	Certificate IV in Veterinary Nursing (Online) Open Colleges
2016 – 2019	Bachelor of Natural Science (Animal Science), Major in Zoology Western Sydney University, NSW
2019	Fundamentals of Chemistry (Single Unit, Online) Murdoch University (Open Universities)

2019	Dealing with Numbers (Single Unit, Online) Swinburne University (Open Universities)
2019	Fear Free Certification Program (Online) Fear Free Companion Animal Euthanasia (Online)
2015 - 2016	Certificate II Animal Studies TAFE WSI (Western Sydney Institute), NSW
1998 - 2011	Tara Anglican School for Girls, NSW Completed High School Certificate

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

August 2018 - Present Role: Veterinary Nurse

Greencross Veterinary Clinic Castle Hill (Volunteer and Paid)

I began work as a volunteer position and was quickly hired as a paid veterinary nurse. I am one of only two nurses working in an extremely busy and fast paced environment, and I am responsible for various roles throughout the clinic, and am involved in all aspects of clinic life.

Some examples of roles include;

- Handle large number of patients and clients
- Assist veterinarian during examinations and surgery
- Assessment and monitoring of animals
- General cleaning
- Prepare surgery/surgical equipment
- Reception duties

- Provide pre and post-operative care
- Administer medications
- Anaesthetics
- X-rays
- Stock ordering
- Tend to clinic emails
- Pathology
- Work individually and as part of a team

2019 - Present

Role: Veterinary Nurse Rouse Hill Family Vets

I have commenced casual work for Dr Belinda Parsons at Rouse Hill Family Vets. Some examples of roles include;

- General veterinary nursing duties
- Assist in surgery
- Assist in house call visits
- Assist in euthanasia and palliative care
- Provide fear free care to animals

2009 - Present

Role: Junior Accounts Officer

Aldridge Traffic Controllers, Rydalmere, NSW

- Aid in maintaining financial records
- Payroll
- Accounts Payable/Receivable
- Stock ordering
- Preparing reports

- Invoice processing
- Record keeping
- Reception duties
- Manufacturing of traffic controllers and traffic lights

2017 - 2019

Role: Volunteer Farm Hand

Hawkesbury Campus Farm, Western Sydney University

- Observe and assist with cattle, sheep and deer
- Mustering
- Drafting
- Vaccination
- Drenching
- Use of the crush
- Ear-tag
- Restraints
- Condition score

2017 -2019

Role: Teaching Assistant and Demonstrator Volunteer Western Sydney University, Hawkesbury

- Prepare for laboratory and field work practical classes
- Set up equipment including microscopes, biological matter, learning materials
- Assist in marking
- Prepare and help facilitate classes
- Provide assistance to students throughout field and laboratory classes
- Classes included Animal Reproduction, Human Animal Interactions, Animal Nutrition and Feeding
- Subjects include knowledge of chemistry and biology

August 2018 - December 2018

Role: Volunteer Veterinary Nurse

Hawkesbury Equine Veterinary Centre

I volunteered as a veterinary nurse and stable hand at the Hawkesbury Equine Veterinary Centre for a short time throughout 2018. I undertook this volunteer work to gain more experience and understanding of other clinic processes and procedures. Some examples of roles include;

- Assist in surgery and examinations
- General cleaning
- Provide food and water

- Prepare surgery
- Anaesthetic monitoring
- Prepare surgical equipment

April 2016 - May 2016

Role: Volunteer Animal Attendant

Animal Referral Hospital Baulkham Hills

- General cleaning duties
- Provide critical care for animals
- Assist/or observe CPR
- Assist in monitoring animals
- Assist veterinarians and nurses in an emergency environment

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Proficient in the use of the Veterinary Rx Works Program, Merlin, MYOB,
 Scientia, and Microsoft Excel, among other Microsoft programs
- Skilled in the use of IDEXX in-house pathology, IM3 dental, and isoflurane anaesthetic system
- Proficient in all aspect of social media and online marketing

OTHER SKILLS

- Strong written and verbal communication skills
- Compassionate and empathetic
- Work well as an individual or as a member of a team
- Ambitious and work to a very high standard
- Possess a strong willingness to learn
- Active listening skills

MEMBERSHIPS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Golden Key International Honour Society (academic achievement)
- WIRES certified rescuer and carer
- Australian Wildlife Society Student Member
- Fear Free Certified Professionals
- Achieved a 5.957 GPA throughout Bachelor's degree
- Awarded a place among the golden key international honours society
- Obtained a statement of excellence in Certificate II Animal Studies

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- Photography (Completed Certificate III in Visual Arts and Contemporary Craft)
- Water Polo (ex-captain of high school team)
- · Physical fitness including weight lifting and swimming
- Bush walking

REFERENCES

Greencross Veterinary Clinic

Contact Person: Deb Lowe, Practice Manager

Phone: 02 9146 1167

Rouse Hill Family Vets

Contact Person: Dr Belinda Parsons, Practice Owner/Veterinarian

Phone: 0417 497 550

Hawkesbury Equine Veterinary Centre

Contact Person: Anne Parbery, Practice Manager

Phone: 02 4577 4611

Western Sydney University

Contact Person: Dr Jason Flesch (University farms and Supervisor for Teaching

Assistant Position) Phone: 02 4570 1392